<resources>
    <!--Home page strings-->
    <string name="app_name">OpenLegendRPG</string>
    <string-array name="navigation_drawer_items_array">
        <item>Home</item>
        <item>Core Rules</item>
        <item>Banes</item>
        <item>Boons</item>
        <item>Feats</item>
        <item>Characters</item>
        <item>Login</item>
        <item>Create Account</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="perks">
        <item>Ageless</item>
        <item>Artisan</item>
        <item>Ascetic</item>
        <item>Attractive</item>
        <item>Brute</item>
        <item>Courageous</item>
        <item>Crowd Favorite</item>
        <item>Disease Immunity</item>

        <item>Divine Agent</item>
        <item>Divine Insight</item>
        <item>Ear of the Emperor</item>
        <item>Extraordinary Presence</item>
        <item>Fugitive</item>
        <item>Idol</item>
        <item>Innocent</item>
        <item>Jack of all Trades</item>

        <item>Legendary Bloodline</item>
        <item>Local Hero</item>
        <item>Lucky</item>
        <item>Merchant</item>
        <item>Natures Ally</item>
        <item>Observant</item>
        <item>Profession</item>
        <item>Pure-Hearted</item>

        <item>Resilient</item>
        <item>Scavenger</item>
        <item>Scent</item>
        <item>Scholar</item>
        <item>Silver Tongue</item>
        <item>Stone Sense</item>
        <item>Street Rat</item>
        <item>Upper Class</item>

        <item>Vagabond</item>
        <item>Warriors Code</item>
        <item>Whisperer to the Wild</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="flaws">
        <item>Absent-Minded</item>
        <item>Addiction</item>
        <item>Ambitions</item>
        <item>BloodLust</item>
        <item>Brash</item>
        <item>Bravado</item>
        <item>Cosmetic Deformity</item>
        <item>Compulsion</item>

        <item>Cowardly</item>
        <item>Dimwitted</item>
        <item>Disabled</item>
        <item>Greedy</item>
        <item>Honest</item>
        <item>Hot Tempered</item>
        <item>Illiterate</item>
        <item>Literal Minded</item>

        <item>Mood Disorder</item>
        <item>Naive</item>
        <item>Overt</item>
        <item>Overweight</item>
        <item>Pacifist</item>
        <item>Phobia</item>
        <item>Proud</item>
        <item>Psychotic</item>

        <item>Short-Winded</item>
        <item>Sick</item>
        <item>Socially Awkward</item>
        <item>Stubborn</item>
        <item>Uncoordinated</item>
        <item>Vengeful</item>
        <item>Zealous</item>
    </string-array>
    <string
        name="OLRPG_logo">Open legend rpg logo
    </string>

    <string
        name="OLRPG_backdrop">Open legend rpg backdrop
    </string>

    <string
        name="description_body1_header">What is Open Legend?
    </string>

    <string
        name="description_body1">Open Legend is a tabletop roleplaying game (or RPG) in which the players play the part of mighty heroes and wicked villains in order to tell stories of epic proportion. In each game of Open Legend, the intrepid characters will fight mythic beasts, break ancient curses, unravel mysterious enigmas, discover treasures untold, and more. Open Legend is a streamlined system designed to let you tell big stories using small rules. The rules get complex when they need to, but never cumbersome, and wherever they could be cut out or simplified, they have been. Some of the highlights at the heart of Open Legend are explained below."
    </string>

    <string
        name="description_body2_header">Unhindered Character Creation
    </string>

    <string
        name="description_body2">With Open Legend, every ability you choose for your character is a new decision. You are never required to choose from a short list, and every character has the potential to access every ability. The story you choose to tell with these abilities and how they manifest, is an opportunity to let your imagination run wild. Select the abilities that match your vision and ignore the ones that don’t. Or, you can get started with one of our quick builds. Either way, the best part is, it is fast and simple but still has lots of potential for intricate and complex characters, if that is what you are looking for. Complex and simple characters can both play a meaningful role in an Open Legend game.
    </string>

    <string
        name="description_body3_header">Banes and Boons
    </string>

    <string
        name="banesAndBoons__description">Open Legend features a collection of banes and boons that any character can use as long as they possess the appropriate attributes. Banes allow you to stun your enemies, set them ablaze, or otherwise hinder them with devastating status effects. Boons are perks that you grant yourself or allies, such as magical healing, damage resistance, and flight. In Open Legend, no fighter is just a walking meat shield with a blade. He’s a trained combatant who can stun, blind, cripple, and hurl his foes across the battlefield. And when a sorceress summons an icy storm from the skies, she decides at the time of casting if she also wants it to slow, knockdown, or immobilize her enemies.
    </string>

    <string
        name="diceWithoutLimit">Dice Without Limit
    </string>

    <string
        name="diceDescription">In Open Legend, dice explode! That means that whenever any die rolls maximum, you get to reroll it and add the new roll to your total, ad infinitum. We love to tell a good story, but rolling dice is just so much fun, we thought that occasionally, you should get to roll a lot of them. The volatile nature of exploding dice makes every roll count, and every session of Open Legend is full of tense moments when the tides can turn at a moment’s notice, for better or worse.
    </string>

    <string
        name="genrePossibility">Any Genre, Endless Possibilities
    </string>

    <string
        name="genrePossibilityDescription">The core rules are written to reflect a high fantasy, sword and sorcery setting, but Open Legend was purposefully designed to be open to any genre. The mechanics of the game focus on effects rather than flavor so that your gaming table can tell whatever kind of story it wants. Struggle for survival in a post-apocalyptic zombie wasteland. Soar amidst the clouds on your crystal-powered airship in a steampunk inspired campaign of swashbuckling sky pirates. Explore an alien-infested space station abandoned at the edge of the universe. The possibilities are endless.
    </string>

    <!--End of home page strings-->

    strings iun vals

    <!--Beginning of Core Rules strings-->
    <string
        name="next">Next\n Chapter
    </string>
    <string
        name="table">Table of Contents
    </string>
    <string
        name="previous">Previous\n Chapter
    </string>
    <string
        name="introTitle">Introduction: This is Your Story. Tell it.
    </string>
    <string
        name="chapter1Title">Chapter 1: Character Creation
    </string>
    <string
        name="chapter2Title">Chapter 2: Actions and Attributes
    </string>
    <string
        name="chapter3Title">Chapter 3: Banes and Boons
    </string>

    <string
        name="chapter4Title">Chapter 4: Feats
    </string>
    <string
        name="chapter5Title">Chapter 5: Perks and Flaws
    </string>
    <string
        name="chapter6Title">Chapter 6: Wealth and Equipment
    </string>
    <string
        name="chapter7Title">Chapter 7: Combat
    </string>
    <string
        name="chapter8Title">Chapter 8: Running the Game
    </string>
    <string
        name="chapter9Title">Chapter 9: Special Equipment
    </string>
    <!--Beginning of intro strings-->
    <string
        name="whatDefinesOpenLegend">What Defines Open Legend?
    </string>
    <string
        name="theActionRoll">The Core Mechanic: The Action Roll
    </string>
    <string
        name="treasures"><b>Greater Treasures Lie Within</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description1">Why Open Legend?
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description2">If you have played roleplaying games in the past, you may be wondering What makes Open Legend worth my time? What makes it different?
The secret’s in the title: Open. Everything about the game has been built to open up the doors of possibility so that every table tells a legend worth telling. Here are a few of the possibilities that Open Legend offers.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description3"><b>Open Source.</b> That’s right. The unabridged core rules are available on the website and the Open Legend Community License allows for publication of both commercial as well as non-commercial derivative works using the system. We know the public will love the game as much as we do, and we hope they’ll spread the love by publishing their own adventures, rules supplements, and more.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description4"><b>Open Dice.</b> In Open Legend, dice explode! That means that whenever ANY die rolls maximum, you get to reroll it and add the new roll to your total, ad infinitum. The volatile nature of dice rolling makes every roll count, and each session of Open Legend is full of tense moments when the tides can turn at a moment’s notice, for better or worse.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description5"><b>Open Legend.</b> You get to tell the story that you want to tell, with the characters you want to play. You aren’t tied down to specific class, archetype, or race combinations. The only limit is your imagination (and maybe the GM’s veto power). Rather than a list of set classes with a menu of skills to pick from, you start the game with attribute points that you spend as you wish to give your character the powers they need.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description6">Welcome to Open Legend, a tabletop roleplaying game (or RPG) in which the players take the part of mighty heroes and wicked villains in order to tell stories of epic proportion. As in the vignettes above, every game of Open Legend revolves around intrepid characters performing heroic deeds. They will fight mythic beasts, outsmart cunning foes, break ancient curses, crack baffling cases, discover untold treasures, and more.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description7">If you have never played a roleplaying game before, you can think of it as a movie in which the actors make up the script (and even much of the plot) as the movie is being shot. One player, called the <b>Game Master</b> (or GM), acts as producer, director, and writer. The GM establishes the setting, creates the antagonists, and develops enough plot to get the other players started. The GM also acts out the part of the villains and neutral characters in the story.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description8">The rest of the players take the role of <b>Player Characters</b> (or PCs). The PCs are the protagonists of the story. In a high fantasy setting, one PC might be a dwarven warrior with a lust for gems, another an immortal elven wizard whose only desire is knowledge, and still another a half-angelic priest who travels the world in order to inspire others to act justly. In another game of Open Legend, the players might star as a rag tag crew of space pirates living from score to score on their barely functioning merchant class starship. All the common tropes could make an appearance: the reckless pilot, the brash captain with a troubled past, the hired gun, the stowaway, and the engineer who gets along with the ship better than with the crew.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description9">Whatever the motivation of their characters, the players share a common goal: to take the plot and setting established by the GM and have fun. At some tables, this might look like J.R.R Tolkien’s Lord of the Rings. In others, it might look more like <i>Monty Python</i> and the <i>Holy Grail</i>. Whatever fun looks like at your table, Open Legend will be a part of it.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description10">This is your story. Tell it.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description11">Open Legend is a game designed for players who want enough rules to make a game fair, but not so many that the rules interfere with the fun or imagination. Open Legend provides a way to make sure that the game is balanced while adjusting the story of character abilities on the fly. The rules should be robust, but their only value is in telling a story.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description12">For example, Open Legend’s streamlined systems for secondary effects (banes) and multi-target attacks mean that all characters use the same mechanics to craft unique attacks. In a fantasy campaign, an elemental mage might blast a fork of lightning to damage and stun his foes. A star trooper in a far future campaign might shoot an energy beam to create the very same effect. The rules for both attacks are the same regardless of the story you are using the mechanics to tell.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description13">As storytellers, we love intricate plotlines that feature characters of depth and beauty. But as gamers, we also love rolling dice. If all we wanted to do with our friends was tell stories, we would write a novel together or join an improv theater group.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description14">What we want to do is game. And that means we need rules.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description15">Without well-defined rules, the decisions made by players and GMs can seem arbitrary or inconsistent. The GM may feel overburdened by a constant need to recall past rulings that they have made, and the players may feel like their decisions don’t actually matter because the GM can interpret them however they want. This is the opposite of how a baseball ref operates. The ref doesn’t need to create new rules for every play that they call. The rules of the game are already spelled out. They just need to interpret and apply them.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description16">Open Legend was designed to provide enough rules so that players have a clear framework to guide their play, but not so many rules that the game gets bogged down by them. You spend your day job worrying about bookkeeping and policies. We don’t want the gaming table to feel like that, and we designed Open Legend to focus on the fun rather than the homework.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description17">For example, you won’t have long lists of resources to manage. Any abilities that you can use or spells you can cast in Open Legend can be used at will. Likewise, spellcasters, psions, and techies don’t need to worry about poring over page after page of power descriptions in order to make the right choices. Instead, Open Legend uses a system of <b>banes</b> and <b>boons</b>, or status effects, that any character can apply if they are built to do so.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description18">Other mechanics that will ensure that you can focus on the story you want to tell include simplified wealth and encumbrance systems. In Open Legend, you’ll never need to record a single gold piece on your character sheet or even think about how many pounds your revolver weighs.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description19">Open Legend straddles the line between storytelling and rules mechanics by giving the best of both worlds. It emphasizes both storytelling and strategy at the same time, placing less restrictions on both.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description20">We hope that we’ve built a game for players who love to tell a good story but don’t want every decision to be made on a whim.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description21">We hope that we’ve built a game for players who love to shake the dice and see them roll but don’t want to spend hours min-maxing their characters.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description22">Most of all, we hope that we’ve built a game for players like you.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description23">Most meaningful tasks that a character attempts in Open Legend will be determined by the roll of dice.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description24">To determine the outcome, you roll 1d20 plus any bonus dice granted by your character’s attribute that is most relevant to the task. Any dice that roll the maximum possible explode, which means you can roll them again and add the new total to your action roll as well. Continue rerolling dice until none of them explode.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description25">Add all of the dice together to find your action roll total. If your total is equal to or greater than the action’s Challenge Rating, then you succeed. Otherwise, the GM decides that you either succeed with a twist or fail in a way that allows the story to progress.
    </string>
    <string
        name="actionRoll">THE ACTION ROLL
    </string>
    <string
        name="actionRoll2">Roll 1d20 + attribute dice (all dice explode)
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description26"><b>If the action roll…</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description27"><b>then the result is…</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description28">equals or exceeds the Challenge Rating,
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description29">the player succeeds.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description30">is less than the Challenge Rating,
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description31">the player succeeds with a twist.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description32">- OR -
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description33">the player fails but the story progresses. (GM’s Choice)
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description34">Example Action Roll
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description35">An adventuring party is traveling through the Darkwood, a forest cursed with malignant energy and cast in shadows at every turn. The party spies a gathering of lights in the distance ahead. At the same time, though, a Shade Demon has crept up behind the heroes. The GM tells Imladril, the elven ranger who is at the back of the marching order, to make a Perception roll against a Challenge Rating of 18. Imladril’s Perception score of 5 grants him a 2d6 bonus to Perception action rolls, so he grabs 1d20 + 2d6 and lets them fly.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description36">Imladril rolls a 7 on the d20, and the d6s come up 1 and 6. Since the 6 explodes, the die is rolled again and it comes up a 3, for a grand total of 17 (7+1+6+3), just shy of the required 18. The GM decides to allow Imladril to <b>succeed with a twist</b>, so the GM rules that Imladril hears the demon fast enough to alert the party, but the demon is already within melee distance and is able to knock the ranger’s bow out of his hands before the combat begins.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description37">Alternatively, the GM could decide that Imladril <b>fails, but the story progresses.</b> For example, the GM rules that the demon is able to grab the ranger and drag him silently into the darkness completely unbeknownst to the rest of the party distracted by the lights in the distance.
    </string>
    <string
        name="intro_Description38">Action rolls and exploding dice are just the start of what makes Open Legend a blast to play. Read on to discover how to build the characters you’ve always wanted to play, equip them for adventure, explore unknown worlds, and perform epic feats of heroism.
    </string>
    <string
        name="acquiringFeats">Acquiring Feats
    </string>
    <string
        name="acquiringFeatDescription">During your adventurers, the GM will award you Experience Points (or XP) for accomplishing quests and driving the story forward. Every time you gain a point of XP, you also gain one feat point that can be used to purchase new feats just as you did during character creation. You do not have to spend these feat points when you gain them. You can feel free to save any unused feat points to be used at a later time.
    </string>
    <!--Beginning of chapter 1 strings-->
    <string
        name="Button1"><b>Step 1: Describe Your Character</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Button2"><b>Step 2: Choose Attributes</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Button3"><b>Quick Build</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Button4"><b>Custom Build</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Button5"><b>Record Attribute Dice</b>
    </string>

    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description1">Before you can start telling your story, you’ll need a character to play. This chapter will offer you step-by-step instructions to create your own hero. In Open Legend, you typically begin as a level one character. As you complete missions or quests and gain more experience as a hero, you’ll level up and gain more power. These rules explain how to create a character starting at level one. Later, you’ll learn what to do when you level up.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description2">Before reading on, take a minute and think of your favorite movies, books, or video games.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description3"><i>Who were the characters you identified with?</i>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description4"><i>Who inspired you?</i>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description5">Now that you’ve got some of your favorites in mind, let’s create your character.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description6">Open Legend is a role playing game, which means your character will need more depth than merely a selection of attributes, feats, perks, and gear. To make your character come to life, add some of the following details. If you can’t think of anything yet, try to fill in the blanks during your first couple of play sessions as you get to know your character better.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description7"><b>A heroic name.</b> Be sure to check with your GM to see if they have any particular setting in mind. Phil the Fighter would feel quite out of place next to Therilas Windcaster and Gorion Skullcleaver.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description8"><b>Your race.</b> Your decision of race is limited only by your imagination, the setting, and the constraints provided by your GM. A typical fantasy campaign might feature dwarves, elves, halflings, celestials, and dragon-blooded. If you are playing in a futuristic space opera on the fringes of the galaxy, your GM might have several alien races to choose from. Some campaigns, such as a mystery of Lovecraftian horror, might allow only for regular old humans. Really, though, as long as it is approved by your GM, you can play anything you would like, whether that’s a psionic humanoid tiger, a 3-inch tall pixie, or anything in between.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description9">As part of deciding your race, you should also choose your <b>size</b>: small, medium, or large. A medium character is roughly the size of an average human. Small creatures range from about 2 - 4 feet in height, while large creatures are about 7 - 10 feet tall. A large creature occupies a 10’x10’ square in combat and has a 10’ reach (see Chapter 7: Combat for details). The GM may assign advantage or disadvantage during situations in which your size is relevant. For example, small creatures may gain advantage on rolls to hide and receive disadvantage on rolls to kick down a door. Likewise, large creatures might suffer disadvantage on attack rolls when fighting in confined spaces but gain advantage on rolls to intimidate smaller creatures.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description10">At the GM’s discretion, you may choose to be even smaller or larger than the listed sizes. A large creature’s reach is always equal to the length of its base. So, a giant with a 15’x15’ base would have a 15’ reach. All creatures always have at least a 5’ reach.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description11">No Racial Abilities or Adjustments?
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description12">In Open Legend, races do not provide specific mechanical costs and benefits. Instead, you’ll have a chance to further define your character in a later step of character creation by choosing your perks and flaws. Some or all of your decisions at that stage may be influenced by your race, and you are encouraged to explain to the rest of your group how your race informs your choice of perks and flaws. For example, if you are playing a psionic humanoid tiger, you might choose the scent perk to highlight your hunter’s bloodline and the observant perk to simulate your extrasensory perception. Likewise, you could select the hot tempered flaw to represent the savage animal that still lurks beneath your intelligent outer shell.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description13"><b>Two exceptional physical traits.</b> Think of the first two features that other characters notice when they see you. Do your eyes glow red when you are angry? Are you seven feet tall? Is your hair a rainbow hue?
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description14"><b>Two defining social traits.</b> Maybe you stutter when you’re nervous. Maybe you don’t trust anyone until they’ve proven themselves to you. Or, perhaps, you are a winsome bard who almost always talks in sing-song. Your two social traits should be characteristics that others will learn shortly after getting to know you.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description15"><b>A secret.</b> Your secret is something that other characters probably won’t find out about until they’ve gotten to know you quite well. It’s also a seed for great adventure that the GM can weave into the campaign.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description16">Example Character Secrets
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description17">Before Volkor changed his name and began wandering the land as a barbarian sellsword, he was heir to the throne.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description18">Sir Thomas Tuckburrough served as an assassin for the local thieves guild until a job went bad and he murdered an innocent child—that’s when he began his road to the priesthood.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description19">Talia suffered from a horrible car accident as a youth. She only survived because a mad street doctor found her body and kept it alive with a number of cybernetic implants that have left her half machine, both physically and mentally.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description20">Attributes are the backbone of every character in Open Legend. They define what your character can and can’t do—the spheres they excel in, as well as their greatest weaknesses. Whenever your character attempts a heroic action in Open Legend, you’ll look to your attributes to see how well you succeed or fail.
    </string>

    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description21">In Open Legend, attributes are divided into four categories: physical, social, mental, and extraordinary.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description22">A character’s skill with each attribute is expressed as a score from 0 (completely unpracticed) to 9 (superhuman). A character cannot use an extraordinary attribute if they have a score of zero, though physical, social, and mental attributes may still be used untrained.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description23">The average commoner or craftsman usually has scores ranging from 1 - 3 in several physical, social, and mental attributes. Extraordinary attributes are generally reserved for characters of power and note.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description24">The Attributes at a Glance tables provide a quick overview of some of the common actions that each attribute will help you accomplish. All of the attributes are explained in further detail in Chapter 2: Actions and Attributes.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description25">Physical Attributes at a Glance
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description26"><b>Agility</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description27">Dodge attacks, move with stealth, perform acrobatics, shoot a bow, pick a pocket
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description28"><b>Fortitude</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description29">Resist poison, shrug off pain, survive in a desert, wear heavy armor
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description30"><b>Might</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description31">Swing a maul, jump over a chasm, break down a door, wrestle a foe to submission
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description32">Mental Attributes at a Glance
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description33"><b>Learning</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description34">Recall facts about history, arcane magic, the natural world, or any information you picked up from an external source
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description35"><b>Logic</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description36">Innovate a new crafting method, decipher a code, jury-rig a device, get the gist of a language you don’t speak
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description37"><b>Perception</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description38">Sense ulterior motives, track someone, catch a gut feeling, spot a hidden foe, find a secret door
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description39"><b>Will</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description40">Maintain your resolve, resist torture, study long hours, stay awake on watch, stave off insanity
    </string>

    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description41">Social Attributes at a Glance
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description42"><b>Deception</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description43">Tell a lie, bluff at cards, disguise yourself, spread rumors, swindle a sucker
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description44"><b>Persuasion</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description45">Negotiate a deal, convince someone, haggle a good price, pry information
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description46"><b>Presence</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description47">Give a speech, sing a song, inspire an army, exert your force of personality, have luck smile upon you
    </string>

    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description48">Extraordinary Attributes at a Glance
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description49"><b>Alteration</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description50">Change shape, alter molecular structures, transmute one material into another
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description51"><b>Creation</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description52">Channel higher powers, manifest something from nothing, regenerate, divinely bolster
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description53"><b>Energy</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description54">Create and control the elements—fire, cold, electricity
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description55"><b>Entropy</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description56">Disintegrate matter, kill with a word, create undead, sicken others
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description57"><b>Influence</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description58">Control the minds of others, speak telepathically, instill fear, create illusory figments, cloak with invisibility
    </string>

    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description59"><b>Movement</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description60">Teleport, fly, hasten, telekinetically push
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description61"><b>Prescience</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description62">See the future, read minds or auras, view from afar, detect magic or evil, communicate with extraplanar entities
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description63"><b>Protection</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description64">Protect from damage, break supernatural influence, dispel magic, exile extradimensional beings
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description65">In Open Legend, you get to define your character’s strengths and weaknesses by choosing the attributes that fit your character concept. Described below are several methods by which you can assign your attributes.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description66">Quick Build
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description67">If you are new to roleplaying games, or are just looking to get your character built quickly, choose one of the attribute sets listed in the Attribute Quick Builds table. Assign the scores listed to the attributes that define the type of character you want to play. The rest of your attributes begin with a score of zero.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description68">ATTRIBUTE QUICK BUILDS
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description69"><b>Specialized Hero</b>
    </string>

    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description70">5, 4, 3, 2, 2, 2
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description71"><b>Well-rounded Hero</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description72">4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 1, 1
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description73"><b>Jack of All Trades</b>
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description74">3, 3, 3, 3, 3, 2, 2, 2, 1
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description75">Custom Build
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter1_Description76">If you would like more control over your attributes, you can purchase them to create your own set. With this method, at first level, you have a budget of 40 attribute points to spend, and the cost of each score is defined in the Purchasing Attributes table. The highest any score can reach at first level is 5, and you don’t have to spend all of your points at character creation.

<b>Description.</b> This entry simply provides a general idea of what the feat could look like in the story. Because feats generally provide mechanical benefits that aren’t tied to specific sources, you can interpret the look and feel of your feat in a way that best fits your character concept and campaign setting. For example, a paladin in a typical fantasy setting might use the companion feat to enlist the assistance of a noble squire, while a technologist in a futuristic campaign might use the same feat to create an automaton combat droid. In both cases, the feat functions the same even though it is described differently.

<b>Effect.</b> This entry indicates the mechanical effects of the feat on the rules of the game.
    </string>
















    <!--Beginning of chapter2 strings-->
    <!--Beginning of chapter3 strings-->
    <string
        name="CH3Button1">Telling Your Story with Banes and Boons
    </string>
    <string
        name="CH3Button2">Invoking Banes and Boons
    </string>
    <string
        name="CH3Button3">Reading a Bane Description
    </string>
    <string
        name="CH3Button4">Reading a Boon Description
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description1">Banes and boons are a huge part of what makes Open Legend so open. They represent the endless possibilities of effects that your character can have on other characters beyond simply dealing damage. Banes are negative conditions that you inflict upon your foes, such as by stunning them, demoralizing them, or setting them on fire. Boons are the opposite: helpful effects that assist your allies by allowing them to fly, shrug off damage, or move with extraordinary speed.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description2">Banes and boons are not tied to specific spells, attacks, or items. Any character can invoke any bane or boon as long as the character possesses a prerequisite attribute. Attribute prerequisites are meant to limit the power of banes and boons so that they scale as your character gains power. That is why, for example, your first level necromancer can invoke the <i>blindsight</i> boon with their Entropy attribute of 5, but won’t be able to invoke the <i>insubstantial</i> boon for themself or their allies until they gain enough experience to increase their Entropy to 7
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description3">Because <i>Open Legend</i> focuses on separating the mechanics from the story, when you invoke a bane or boon, you get to decide what it looks like in the narrative. For example, did you knockdown a foe with an agile sweep kick, a herculean shove, or a telekinetic thrust? When you grant your allies <i>resistance</i>, do they become coated in armor of ice or are they protected by a swarm of droids that surround them and deflect attacks?
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description4">With Great Power Comes Great Responsibility
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description5">When you browse these lists, you will find that your attributes grant access to far more banes and boons than you could typically make use of. Sometimes, attributes can mean different things for different types of characters. For example, imagine using the Alteration attribute to invoke the <i>shapeshift</i> boon - a Druid would do so to turn into a massive bear, while a genetically enhanced military operative might assume the identity of a high profile enemy commander. These examples of using <i>shapeshift</i> make sense and follow our normal expectations from similar stories, but Alteration also grants access to the <i>invisible</i> boon. This can be confusing, because having access to a bane or boon might make you feel that you should use it, but that’s not necessarily the case. The best time to use a bane or boon is when it adds to the story and makes the game more fun for everyone.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description6">In Open Legend, we use the rules to make sure the game is fair and that everyone gets equal opportunity to drive the story forward—we don’t use the rules to ensure the game is logical. Whether or not a story makes sense or is enjoyable is a matter of personal preference. Open Legend expects that these details will be worked out between the players and the GM during a game. Certain attributes give you access to an incredible toolbox of banes and boons, but it is the responsibility of everyone playing the game to respect each other’s wish to tell a story that the group can get excited about. So, while your Druid with Alteration might not have a good excuse to become <i>invisible</i>, the rules make it possible just in case, and in the process it also becomes possible to play an alien psychic warrior that uses Alteration to bend waves of light and become <i>invisible</i>.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description7">To invoke a bane, the primary method is to succeed at an appropriate attribute roll using one of your target’s defense scores as the Challenge Rating, as indicated in the bane description. An alternate method of invoking a bane is to make a successful damaging attack that exceeds the target’s defense by 10 or more. When this happens, you may apply one bane of a power level less than or equal to the attribute you used for the attack. In order to apply a bane, your attack roll must equal or exceed the appropriate defense for that bane. If your attack targeted multiple foes, you may apply the bane to each qualifying target. While targets may be affected by multiple banes, you may not stack banes. That is, a target cannot be inflicted with a bane it is currently suffering from, unless specified in the bane’s effect (e.g. fatigued).
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description8">Additional details about invoking banes and boons, such as attack range and targeting multiple creatures, can be found in Chapter 7: Combat.
    </string>

    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description9">Each bane description includes the following elements.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description10"><b>Power Level.</b> This number indicates the required attribute score needed to inflict the bane. If multiple power levels are listed (such as 2 / 4 / 6), then the bane can be inflicted at multiple tiers of power. The <i>persistent damage</i> bane, for example, deals increased damage as you inflict it at higher power levels.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description11"><b>Attack Attributes.</b> This is a list of the attribute or attributes that can be used to inflict the bane. As long as you possess at least one of the listed attributes at a score greater than or equal to the power level, then you can inflict the bane.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description12"><b>Attack.</b> This list indicates what type of attack roll to make when inflicting the bane. Each entry consists of an attribute that the attacking player should roll and the defense score targeted by the attack. If the attacker’s roll equals or exceeds the target’s defense score, then the bane is inflicted.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description13"><b>Duration.</b> A bane typically remains in effect until the target resists it by using the <i>resist</i> banes action, hence most banes have a duration of “resist ends”. If a target fails three resist rolls against a bane, the bane can no longer be resisted. It persists for an extended duration indicated in parentheses.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description14"><b>Description.</b> This entry simply provides a general idea of what the bane could look like in the story.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description15"><b>Effect.</b> This entry indicates the mechanical effects of the bane on the rules of the game.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description16">Each boon description includes the following elements.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description17"><b>Power Level.</b> This number indicates the required attribute score needed to invoke the boon. If multiple power levels are listed (such as 2 / 4 / 6), then the boon can be invoked at multiple tiers of power. The <i>heal</i> boon, for example, heals more damage as you invoke it at higher power levels. The power level of a boon also determines the Challenge Rating of the attribute roll to invoke the boon. The CR equals 10 + 2 x Power Level.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description18"><b>Attributes.</b> This is a list of the attribute or attributes that can be used to invoke the boon. As long as you possess at least one of the listed attributes at a score greater than or equal to the Power Level, then you can invoke the boon.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description19"><b>Invocation Time.</b> The required time that it takes to invoke the boon. Most boons have an invocation time of 1 major action. For boons that have a longer time, you must spend the entire invocation time concentrating on nothing other than invoking the boon. If you are interrupted, you must start the casting over.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description20"><b>Duration.</b> Most boons have a duration of “sustain persists”, which indicates that the invoker must use a sustain action every round in order to keep the boon in effect. If you have a boon in effect and don’t sustain it, the boon’s effects cease at the end of your turn. Because sustaining a boon is a minor action, which can only be taken once per turn, you can typically sustain only one boon at a time. You do not need to sustain a boon on the round in which it is invoked as long as you are not sustaining any other boons.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description21"><b>Description.</b> This entry simply provides a general idea of what the boon could look like in the story.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter3_Description22"><b>Effect.</b> This entry indicates the mechanical effects of the boon on the rules of the game.
    </string>

    <!--Beginning of chapter4 strings-->

    <string
        name="CH4Button1">Acquiring Feats
    </string>
    <string
        name="CH4Button2">Reading a Feat Description
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter4_Description1">In this chapter, you’ll find complete descriptions of all of the feats available to customize your character in Open Legend. Feats are used to define your character’s specializations—the actions, tasks, and abilities they excel at beyond all others. Some feats will enhance your major actions, such as by allowing you to multi-attack with reduced disadvantage, while others will grant you completely new powers, such as the ability to change your shape.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter4_Description2">During your adventurers, the GM will award you Experience Points (or XP) for accomplishing quests and driving the story forward. Every time you gain a point of XP, you also gain one feat point that can be used to purchase new feats just as you did during character creation. You do not have to spend these feat points when you gain them. You can feel free to save any unused feat points to be used at a later time.
    </string>


    <string
        name="Chapter4_Description3">Each feat description includes the following elements.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter4_Description4"><b>Title.</b> The name of the feat. Some feats contain multiple tiers, rising in power with each new tier. If a feat contains multiple tiers, these will be indicated in parentheses after the title (e.g., “Alternate Form (I - II)”).
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter4_Description5"><b>Cost.</b> This is the number of feat points required to purchase the feat. If the feat has multiple tiers, the cost is the same for each tier and must be paid every time the feat is purchased at a new tier <i>unless otherwise noted in the feat description</i>. So, to access the Tier 5 ability of a feat, you must pay for the feat 5 times. If a feat does not have a noted exception it can only be purchased once.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter4_Description6"><b>Prerequisites.</b> Many feats have specific requirements that must be met before a character can purchase the feat. Prerequisites may take the form of a minimum attribute score, another feat, or a special requirement. If a feat has multiple tiers with different prerequisites, the requirements for each tier are separated by a slash.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter4_Description7"><b>Description.</b> This entry simply provides a general idea of what the feat could look like in the story. Because feats generally provide mechanical benefits that aren’t tied to specific sources, you can interpret the look and feel of your feat in a way that best fits your character concept and campaign setting. For example, a paladin in a typical fantasy setting might use the <i>companion</i> feat to enlist the assistance of a noble squire, while a technologist in a futuristic campaign might use the same feat to create an automaton combat droid. In both cases, the feat functions the same even though it is described differently.
    </string>
    <string
        name="Chapter4_Description8"><b>Effect.</b> This entry indicates the mechanical effects of the feat on the rules of the game.
    </string>


    <!--Beginning of chapter5 strings-->
    <!--Beginning of chapter6 strings-->
    <!--Beginning of chapter7 strings-->
    <!--Beginning of chapter8 strings-->
    <!--Beginning of chapter9 strings-->
    <!--End of Core Rules strings-->
    <!--End of Login & create strings-->
    <string
        name="login">Login
    </string>
    <string
        name="password">Password
    </string>
    <string
        name="e_mail">Email
    </string>
    <string
        name="tag">Welcome to the world of OpenLegendRPG! Please Create an account or login.
    </string>
    <string
        name="register">Register
    </string>
    <string
        name="re_type_password">Re-type Password
    </string>
    <string
        name="your_name">Username
    </string>
    <!--End of Login & create strings-->

</resources>